<resources>
    <string name="app_name">The Scientists App</string>

    <string name="history_e">

        <![CDATA[Born- - -14 March 1879
 Ulm, Kingdom of Württemberg, German Empire\n \n \n
Died- - -18 April 1955 (aged 76
Princeton, New Jersey, U.S.\n \n \n
Residence- - -	Germany, Italy, Switzerland, Austria (today: Czech Republic), Belgium, United States\n \n \n
Citizenship- - -
 Kingdom of Württemberg (1879–1896)
 Stateless (1896–1901)
 Switzerland (1901–1955)
 Austria of the Austro-Hungarian Empire (1911–1912)
 Germany (1914–1933)
 United States (1940–1955)\n \n \n
Fields- - -	Physics, philosophy\n \n \n
Institutions- - -
 Swiss Patent Office (Bern) (1902–1909)\n
 University of Bern (1908–1909)\n
 University of Zurich (1909–1911)\n
 Charles University in Prague (1911–1912)\n
 ETH Zurich (1912–1914)\n
 Prussian Academy of Sciences (1914–1933)\n
 Humboldt University of Berlin (1914–1917)\n
 Kaiser Wilhelm Institute (director, 1917–1933)\n
 German Physical Society (president, 1916–1918)\n
Leiden University (visits, 1920–)\n \n \n
Institute for Advanced Study (1933–1955) - - -
Caltech (visits, 1931–1933)\n
Alma mater\n
Swiss Federal Polytechnic (1896–1900; B.A., 1900)\n
University of Zurich (Ph.D., 1905)\n
Thesis	Eine neue Bestimmung der Moleküldimensionen (A New Determination of Molecular Dimensions) (1905)\n \n \n
Doctoral advisor- - -	Alfred Kleiner\n \n \n
Other academic advisors- - -	Heinrich Friedrich Weber\n \n \n
Known for- - -
General relativity and special relativity\n
Photoelectric effect\n
E=mc2\n
Theory of Brownian motion\n
Einstein field equations\n
Bose–Einstein statistics\n
Bose–Einstein condensate\n
Gravitational wave\n
Cosmological constant\n
Unified field theory\n
EPR paradox\n \n \n
Influenced- - -
 Ernst G. Straus
 Nathan Rosenv
 Leó Szilárd\n \n \n
Notable awards- - -
 Barnard Medal (1920)
 Nobel Prize in Physics (1921)
 Matteucci Medal (1921)
 ForMemRS (1921)[1]
 Copley Medal (1925)[1]
 Max Planck Medal (1929)
 Time Person of the Century (1999)
 Spouse	Mileva Marić (1903–1919)
 Elsa Löwenthal (1919–1936)
 Children	"Lieserl" (1902–1903?)
 Hans Albert (1904–1973)
 Eduard "Tete" (1910–1965)]]>


    </string>


 <string name="interesting_facts_e">
  <![CDATA[
    Albert Einstein considered himself an agnostic, not an atheist.\n \n \n
    Einstein great breakthroughs came from visual experiments performed in his head rather than the lab.\n \n \n
    Einstein was a slow learner as a child and spoke very slowly.\n \n \n
    The pathologist who made Einstein body autopsy stole his brain and kept it in a jar for 20 years.\n \n \n
    Einstein Nobel Prize money went to his ex-wife as a divorce settlement.\n \n \n
    Einstein was offered the presidency of Israel which he politely declined.\n \n \n
    Einstein Failed his University Entrance Exam and had to reapply a year later.\n \n \n
    Einstein was famous  for having a bad memory. He could not remember names, dates and phone numbers.\n \n \n
    Einstein had an illegitimate daughter born in 1902.\n \n \n
    Einstein, Darwin, Allan Poe & Saddam Hussein, all married their first cousins.\n \n \n
    Austrian physicist Friedrich Hasenohrl published the basic equation E = mc2 a year before Einstein did.\n \n \n
    Albert Einstein eyes remain in a safe box in NYC.\n \n \n
    Yoda, from Star Wars, was modeled after the appearance of Albert Einstein.\n \n \n
    Albert Einstein had no car of his own and he also never learned how to drive.\n \n \n
    Albert Einstein brain had a parietal lobe that was 15% larger than the average brain.\n \n \n
    Galileo Galilei was Albert Einstein favorite scientist.\n \n \n
    Hours before his death, Einstein was still attempting to prove his Theory of Everything.\n \n \n]]>
 </string>


    <string name="stories_of_einstein">

        <![CDATA[
        (1)       One day during a speaking tour, Albert Einstein\'s driver, who often sat at the back of the hall during his lectures, remarked that he could probably give the lecture himself, having heard it so many times. Sure enough, at the next stop on the tour, Einstein and the driver switched places, with Einstein sitting at the back in his driver uniform.\n\n

Having delivered a flawless lecture, the driver was asked a difficult question by a member of the audience. \"Well, the answer to that question is quite simple,\" he casually replied. \"I bet my driver, sitting up at the back there, could answer it!\"

============ ========= ========= ========= =========\n\n\n
(2)   Albert Einstein\'s wife often suggested that he dress more professionally when he headed off to work. \"Why should I?\" he would invariably argue. \"Everyone knows me there.\" When the time came for Einstein to attend his first major conference, she begged him to dress up a bit. \"Why should I?\" said Einstein. \"No one knows me there!\"

============ ========= ========= ========= ========\n\n\n

(3)      Albert Einstein was often asked to explain the general theory of relativity. \"Put your hand on a hot stove for a minute, and it seems like an hour,\" he once declared. \"Sit with a pretty girl for an hour, and it seems like a minute. That\'s relativity!\"

============ ========= ========= ========= =========\n\n\n

(4)      When Albert Einstein was working in Princeton university, one day he was going back home he forgot his home address. The driver of the cab did not recognize him. Einstein asked the driver if he knows Einstein\'s home. The driver said \"Who does not know Einstein\'s address? Everyone in Princeton knows.Do you want to meet him?. Einstein replied \"I am Einstein. I forgot my home address, can you take me there? \"The driver reached him to his home and did not even collect his fare from him.

============ ========= ========= ========= =========\n\n\n

(5)      Einstein was once traveling from Princeton on a train when the conductor came down the aisle, punching the tickets of every passenger. When he came to Einstein, Einstein reached in his vest pocket. He couldn\'t find his ticket, so he reached in his trouser pockets. It wasn\'t there, so he looked in his briefcase but couldn\'t find it. Then he looked in the seat beside him. He still couldn\'t find it.\n\n


The conductor said, \'Dr. Einstein, I know who you are. We all know who you are. I\'m sure you bought a ticket. Don\'t worry about it.\n\n

Einstein nodded appreciatively. The conductor continued down the aisle punching tickets. As he was ready to move to the next car, he turned around and saw the great physicist down on his hands and knees looking under his seat for his ticket.\n\n

The conductor rushed back and said, \'Dr. Einstein, Dr. Einstein, don\'t worry, I know who you are. No problem. You don\'t need a ticket. I\'m sure you bought one.\n\n

Einstein looked at him and said, \'Young man, I too, know who I am. What I don\'t know is where I\'m going.

        ]]>

    </string>
    
    <string name="Theories_e">

        <![CDATA[

        THEORY OF RELATIVITY AND E = mc²\n\n
Einstein\'s \"Zur Elektrodynamik bewegter Körper\" (\"On the Electrodynamics of Moving Bodies\") was received on 30 June 1905 and published 26 September of that same year. It reconciles Maxwell\'s equations for electricity and magnetism with the laws of mechanics, by introducing major changes to mechanics close to the speed of light. This later became known as Einstein\'s special theory of relativity.

Consequences of this include the time-space frame of a moving body appearing to slow down and contract (in the direction of motion) when measured in the frame of the observer. This paper also argued that the idea of a luminiferous aether—one of the leading theoretical entities in physics at the time—was superfluous.[131]

In his paper on mass–energy equivalence, Einstein produced E = mc2 from his special relativity equations.[132] Einstein\'s 1905 work on relativity remained controversial for many years, but was accepted by leading physicists, starting with Max Planck.[133][134]\n\n\n\n\n

ZERO POINT ENERGY\n\n
Main article: Zero-point energy
In a series of works completed from 1911 to 1913, Planck reformulated his 1900 quantum theory and introduced the idea of zero-point energy in his \"second quantum theory.\" Soon, this idea attracted the attention of Albert Einstein and his assistant Otto Stern. Assuming the energy of rotating diatomic molecules contains zero-point energy, they then compared the theoretical specific heat of hydrogen gas with the experimental data. The numbers matched nicely. However, after publishing the findings, they promptly withdrew their support, because they no longer had confidence in the correctness of the idea of zero-point energy.[139]\n\n\n\n\n

GRAVITATIONAL WAVES\n\n
In 1916, Einstein predicted gravitational waves,[144][145] ripples in the curvature of spacetime which propagate as waves, traveling outward from the source, transporting energy as gravitational radiation. The existence of gravitational waves is possible under general relativity due to its Lorentz invariance which brings the concept of a finite speed of propagation of the physical interactions of gravity with it. By contrast, gravitational waves cannot exist in the Newtonian theory of gravitation, which postulates that the physical interactions of gravity propagate at infinite speed.

The first, indirect, detection of gravitational waves came in the 1970s through observation of a pair of closely orbiting neutron stars, PSR B1913+16.[146] The explanation of the decay in their orbital period was that they were emitting gravitational waves.[146][147] Einstein\'s prediction was confirmed on 11 February 2016, when researchers at LIGO published direct observation, on Earth, of gravitational waves, exactly one hundred years after the prediction.[146][148][149][150][151]\n\n\n\n\n

WORMHOLES\n\n
Main article: Wormhole
Einstein collaborated with others to produce a model of a wormhole. His motivation was to model elementary particles with charge as a solution of gravitational field equations, in line with the program outlined in the paper \"Do Gravitational Fields play an Important Role in the Constitution of the Elementary Particles?\". These solutions cut and pasted Schwarzschild black holes to make a bridge between two patches.

If one end of a wormhole was positively charged, the other end would be negatively charged. These properties led Einstein to believe that pairs of particles and antiparticles could be described in this way.\n\n\n\n\n


EINSTEIN REFRIGERATOR\n\n
Main article: Einstein refrigerator
In 1926, Einstein and his former student Leó Szilárd co-invented (and in 1930, patented) the Einstein refrigerator. This absorption refrigerator was then revolutionary for having no moving parts and using only heat as an input.[173] On 11 November 1930, U.S. Patent 1,781,541 was awarded to Albert Einstein and Leó Szilárd for the refrigerator. Their invention was not immediately put into commercial production, and the most promising of their patents were acquired by the Swedish company Electrolux.[174]
        ]]>



    </string>


    <string name="history_i">

        <![CDATA[Born---	25 December 1642
[NS: 4 January 1643][1]
Woolsthorpe, Lincolnshire, England\n\n\n
Died---	20 March 1726/7 (aged 84)
[OS: 20 March 1726
 NS: 31 March 1727][1]
Kensington, Middlesex, England\n\n\n
Resting place	---Westminster Abbey\n\n\n
Nationality---	English\n\n\n
Fields	---
Physics Natural philosophy\n
Mathematics Astronomy\n
Alchemy Economics\n\n\n
Institutions---
 University of Cambridge\n
 Royal Society\n
 Royal Mint\n
 Alma mater	Trinity College, Cambridge\n\n\n
Academic advisors---
 Isaac Barrow[2]
 Benjamin Pulleyn[3][4]\n\n\n
 Notable students---
 Roger Cotes
 William Whiston\n\n\n
Known for	---
Newtonian mechanics\n
Universal gravitation\n
Calculus\n
Newton\'s laws of motion\n
Optics Binomial series\n
Principia Newton\'s method\n\n\n
Notable awards---	FRS (1672)[5]


        ]]>


    </string>"
    <string name="interesting_facts_i">

        <![CDATA[

        1. One genius dies, another one is born. Isaac Newton was born in 1642, the same year that Galileo Galilei died.\n\n\n


2. He could have been a farmer. Newton was born to a farming family so the initial plan was for him to take over the farm when he was old enough. Newton tried, but given his lack of interest in the field, was a very poor farmer. Eventually, his uncle managed to convince his mother to let him go to college.\n\n\n

3. He was Master of the Royal Mint. Newton took this job very seriously and personally pursued counterfeiters. Back then counterfeiting was considered high treason and punishable by death. Newton apprehended multiple counterfeiters, his most famous case being that of William Chaloner.\n\n\n

4.He was an alchemist. Probably the weirdest fact about Newton is that he was a firm believer in alchemy. One of his greatest ambitions was to find the philosopher\’s stone – the secret to turning common metals into gold.\n\n\n

5. The \“apple tree\” story never happened. We all know the famous story of how Newton was resting under a tree when an apple fell on his head, creating a famous \"Eureka\” moment and leading to his laws of gravitation. However, that is all apocryphal. By Newton\’s own admission, he merely saw an apple fall from a tree while walking through the garden, although some believe this story to be a myth, as well.\n\n\n

6.The tree is real, though. In fact, as soon as the story became popular, a debate raged over which apple tree was the real one. Nowadays descendants of the original tree can be found at Cambridge. A piece of the original apple tree was even loaned by the Royal Society to NASA who took it into space.\n\n\n

7. He was also a politician. Newton served as a Member of Parliament representing Cambridge on two separate occasions. However, like farming, he had no interest in this. Several accounts mention the fact that Newton only said one thing while in Parliament, asking for a window to be closed.\n\n\n

8. He had an arch rival. The man’s name was Robert Hooke and the two got into a serious dispute over Newton\’s laws of gravitation. Hooke, an accomplished and respected scientist in his own right, claimed that he came up with them first and Newton stole his work. This began a rivalry between the two men that lasted well after Hooke\’s death. By then, Newton became the President of the Royal Society and used his position to his advantage in order to obscure Hooke as much as possible. One story says that Newton even had all portraits of Hooke destroyed.\n\n\n

9. But he did have high-brow friends. Despite his feud with Hooke, Newton was also friends with many other influential scientists of his time. Examples include Christopher Wren, one of the most successful architects of all time, and Edmond Halley (of Halley\’s Comet fame) who paid for the publication of Newton\’s Principia Mathematica.\n\n\n

10. Newton has the most valuable tooth. One of his teeth was sold in 1816 at auction for approx $3,600. In today\’s terms that\’s about $35,000, prompting Guinness World Records to declare it the most valuable tooth in the world.\n\n\n

        ]]>




    </string>
    <string name="stories_of_newton">
        <![CDATA[


COMETS AND APPLE TREES\n\n

One day Isaac was reading a book under an apple tree on the farm. An apple fell out of the tree - bonk! Ow!
Now, for most people that would be the end of the story, but not for Isaac. Not for somebody who just couldn\'t stop asking why all the time.
Why did the apple fall out of the tree? Does everything fall? What makes things fall? Can anything stop things from falling? Are the sun, moon, and stars falling? Why don\'t they ever hit the ground?
So many questions. Newton spent many years answering these questions by thinking and doing experiments. He made up the law of gravity. According to this law everything pulled everything else to itself by a force called gravity. How strong that force is depends on how heavy the things are and how close together.
So even two apples pull toward each other. But, the force is so small that you need a very careful experiment to measure it. The reason that things fall toward the ground is that the earth we live on is so very heavy, and we are so close to it.
Newton\'s law of gravity not only explained how things fall on earth, but how planets move around the sun and how moons move around planets. A friend of his, Edmund Halley, decided to try Newton\'s theory on comets. People had been studying comets for hundreds of years without figuring them out, so he decided to study their reports and compare them to Newton\'s theories.
Up til then people had thought that comets just came and went, and that nobody could know when or why. But Newton\'s law of gravity gave rules that Halley could use to study the records of comets. He found some reports of a big bright comet that he was sure was the same one, coming back every 75 years. He predicted when it would come back next.
If anybody still didn\'t believe Newton, then the appearance of Halley\'s Comet just when Halley had predicted it using Newtons ideas was enough to convince them. Halley\'s comet has come a few times since then, always right on schedule. You\'ll be able to see it on its next trip near the sun and earth when you\'re old enough to be a grandparent.\n\n\n\n

NEWTON AND HOOKE\n\n

Do you know anybody who always has to be first? Maybe its your brother or sister, or a friend. When you say you learned something, they say \"I already knew that\". When you\'re going to do something, they say \"I already did that\".
There was another famous scientist named Robert Hooke who was very jealous of Netwon. Whenever Newton announced he had discovered something, Hooke would say \"I already discovered that first, I just didn\'t tell anybody yet.\" This made Newton very mad.
Everybody makes mistakes sometimes, even very smart people like Newton. One time when Newton made a mistake, Hooke was the first to discover the mistake and tell everybody about it. Newton was mad and embarrassed. He didn\'t like to make mistakes, but he really hated that it was Hooke who figured out the mistake. Newton said that he would never tell anybody about his discoveries again. He didn\'t want to ever have Hooke catch him making a mistake again. In a while though, Newton realized how silly this was and started telling about his discoveries again.
Newton wrote a big book called Principia. This book told all about how things push and pull, and gave lots of examples of how machines work and how things like planets and comets move. It was a very important book, and scientists still like to read it, even though it is more than 300 years old. But guess what happened when he was writing it. Hooke found out about what he was writing and said \"I already discovered that!\" Newton was so angry that he decided not to write the book. It was a good thing that he again realized how silly it is to let somebody else bother you that much. He did finish writing it, and even mentioned some things that Hooke had done.

        ]]>




    </string>
    <string name="theories_i">

       <![CDATA[ MATHEMATICS
Newton\'s work has been said \"to distinctly advance every branch of mathematics then studied\".[20] His work on the subject usually referred to as fluxions or calculus, seen in a manuscript of October 1666, is now published among Newton\'s mathematical papers.[21] The author of the manuscript De analysi per aequationes numero terminorum infinitas, sent by Isaac Barrow to John Collins in June 1669, was identified by Barrow in a letter sent to Collins in August of that year [22]\n\n\n\n


OPTICS\n\n
In 1666, Newton observed that the spectrum of colours exiting a prism in the position of minimum deviation is oblong, even when the light ray entering the prism is circular, which is to say, the prism refracts different colours by different angles.[36][37] This led him to conclude that colour is a property intrinsic to light—a point which had been debated in prior years.\n\n\n\n

MECHANICS AND GRAVITATION\n\n

Newton\'s own copy of his Principia, with hand-written corrections for the second edition
Further information: Writing of Principia Mathematica
In 1679, Newton returned to his work on (celestial) mechanics by considering gravitation and its effect on the orbits of planets with reference to Kepler\'s laws of planetary motion. This followed stimulation by a brief exchange of letters in 1679–80 with Hooke, who had been appointed to manage the Royal Society\'s correspondence, and who opened a correspondence intended to elicit contributions from Newton to Royal Society transactions.[48]\n\n\n\n

CLASSIFICATION OF CUBES AND BEYOND\n\n
Descartes was the most important early influence on Newton the mathematician. Descartes freed plane curves from the Greek and Macedonian limitation to conic sections, and Newton followed his lead by classifying the cubic curves in the plane. He found 72 of the 78 species of cubics. He also divided them into four types, satisfying different equations, and in 1717 Stirling, probably with Newton\'s help, proved that every cubic was one of these four types. Newton also claimed that the four types could be obtained by plane projection from one of them, and this was proved in 1731.[64]


        ]]>
    </string>


    <string name="history_s">
      <![CDATA[

      Born---	Erwin Rudolf Josef Alexander Schrödinger
12 August 1887
Vienna, Austria-Hungary\n\n\n
Died---	4 January 1961 (aged 73)
Vienna, Austria\n\n\n
Citizenship---
Austria
Ireland (from 1948)\n\n\n
Nationality---	Austrian\n\n\n
Fields---	Physics\n\n\n
Institutions---
 University of Breslau
 University of Zürich
 Frederick William University
 University of Oxford
 University of Graz
 Dublin Institute for Advanced Studies
 Ghent University
 Alma mater	University of Vienna\n\n\n
Doctoral advisor---	Friedrich Hasenöhrl[1]\n\n\n
Other academic advisors---	Franz S. Exner[citation needed]\n\n\n
Notable students---
 Linus Pauling[citation needed]
 Felix Bloch[citation needed]
 Brendan Scaife[citation needed]\n\n\n
Known for---
 Schrödinger equation\n
Schrödinger\'s cat\n
Schrödinger method\n
Schrödinger functional\n
Schrödinger group\n
Schrödinger picture\n
Schrödinger field\n
Rayleigh-Schrödinger perturbation\n
Schrödinger logics\n
Schrödinger\'s pure-affine theory\n
Coherent states\n
Energy level\n
Entropy and life\n
Interpretations of quantum mechanics\n
Qualia\n
Quantum biology\n
Quantum superposition\n
Subject–object problem\n
Cat state\n\n\n
Notable awards---	Matteucci Medal (1927)
  Nobel Prize in Physics (1933)
 Max Planck Medal (1937)
 Spouse	Annemarie Bertel (1920–61)[2]


      ]]>

    </string>
    <string name="interesting_facts_s">
     <![CDATA[1. He Was a Believer in the Vedanta Philosophy:\n
    Through out his life his inclination towards philosophy was strong.\n\n\n
    2. He Tried to Unify Physics with Genetics:\n
One of the great works of his later life is the book called \“What is Life?\” In this book Schrödinger tried to answer the question of where life comes from by looking at it from the perspective of physics\n\n\n
        3. A Crater on the Moon is Named After Him:\n
He received many accolades during his life time for his contribution to science and to the world in general\n\n\n
        4. He Had an Irish Passport:\n
Schrödinger had to relocate many times to find a country that would give him a job and be tolerant of his views.\n\n\n
        5. He Won the Nobel Prize in 1933:\n
When he left the University of Berlin to join Oxford he learned that he had won the Nobel Prize for physics of 1933\n\n\n
        6. He Was Against the Prosecution of Jews:\n
He was forced to abandon his studies and join the Austrian-Hungarian army during the First World War.\n\n\n
        7. He Wrote His Greatest Work in a Sanatorium:\n
The Schrödinger equation changed the way scientists looked at particles and allowed them to predict the motion of the particles through wave mechanics\n\n\n
8. His Cat Was both Alive and Dead at the Same Time:\n
The famous thought experiment called Schrödinger\’s cat talks about a cat inside a box with a vile of poison that can be opened by the trigger of a decaying electron.\n\n\n
        9. He Got His PhD at the Age of 23:\n
He was a brilliant student and was homeschooled till the age of 11. He then studied at Vienna\’s Akademisches Gymnasium and later at the University of Vienna. \n\n\n
10. He was Influenced by Schopenhauer:\n
He was born in a religious household and his parents were Protestants but from an early age he was an atheist and a philosopher.


        ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="stories_of_schrodinger">

        SCHRODINGER\'S  CAT \n\n\n

        A long time ago somebody asked the question \"If a tree falls in a forest, and nobody is there, is there still a sound?\" The problem is, do things happen the same when nobody can watch them, and can we ever find out? And what if its not even possible to watch them? Scientists and philosophers have argued about this for a long long long time.
In the last hundred years a lot of scientists have been very disturbed by something called Quantum Mechanics. They all agree about how it works, and that it does work, but they can\'t all agree about what it means. Here\'s an example: if you have very small balls going through a wall that has two very small holes that are close together, you get a strange pattern for how the balls come out on the other side. You might think that you could measure which hole each of the balls went through. Well, the funny thing is that if you do anything that lets you measure which hole they go through, you get a different pattern for the balls coming out on the other side. If everything is very small, you change everything too much just by trying to watch.
Scientists can agree on this much, but can\'t agree on what it means. If you can\'t measure which hole a ball goes through, does it still go through just one of them, or does it do something unexpected? Does it even make sense to talk about which hole it went through when you could never find out?\n\n\n


        Two very famous scientists who couldn\'t agree on the answer were Einstein and Schroedinger. One day Schroedinger explained his opinion to Einstein by talking about his cat. He suggested that you put a cat in a box with a bottle of poison, and the bottle will open and kill the cat at some time that you don\'t know. Then at some later time is the cat dead or alive? Einstein says that it is one or the other, but we can\'t know which until we open the box. Shroedinger says that it is neither - the cat is a mixture of dead and alive, and only becomes one or the other when we open the box.\n\n\n

        Now in case you are worried about Schroedinger and Einstein\'s cats, you should know that they were not only famous for being great scientists, Einstein especially was also famous for being very kind. Besides that, there were a kind of scientist called a theoretician. This means that mostly they came up with ideas about how the world worked and made predictions about what should happen if you did different things. Actually doing the experiments to find out which theoreticians are right is usually the job of experimentalists. The problem with trying to do an real experiment with real cats to find out the answer is that Schroedinger made up the question in a way that makes it impossible to do it. The question is what is happening in the box when you aren\'t making any measurements, so if we do make measurements we\'ve broken the rules of the puzzle.


    </string>
    <string name="theories_s">

        New quantum theory\n\n
In the first years of his career Schrödinger became acquainted with the ideas of quantum theory, developed in the works of Max Planck, Albert Einstein, Niels Bohr, Arnold Sommerfeld, and others. This knowledge helped him work on some problems in theoretical physics, but the Austrian scientist at the time was not yet ready to part with the traditional methods of classical physics.\n\n\n\n


        Creation of wave mechanics\n\n
In January 1926, Schrödinger published in Annalen der Physik the paper \n"Quantisierung als Eigenwertproblem\n"[24] [tr. Quantization as an Eigenvalue Problem] on wave mechanics and presented what is now known as the Schrödinger equation. In this paper, he gave a \"derivation\" of the wave equation for time-independent systems and showed that it gave the correct energy eigenvalues for a hydrogen-like atom. \n\n\n\n



        Work on a Unified Field Theory\n\n
Following his work on quantum mechanics, Schrödinger devoted considerable effort to working on a Unified Field Theory that would unite gravity, electromagnetism, and nuclear forces within the basic framework of General Relativity, doing the work with an extended correspondence with Albert Einstein.\n\n\n\n



        Colour\n\n
One of Schrödinger\'s lesser-known areas of scientific contribution was his work on colour, colour perception, and colorimetry (Farbenmetrik).
    </string>




    <string name="history_m">

        Born---	13 June 1831
Edinburgh, Scotland\n\n\n
Died---	5 November 1879 (aged 48)
Cambridge, England\n\n\n
Citizenship---	British\n\n\n
Nationality---	Scottish\n\n\n
Fields---	Physics and Mathematics\n\n\n
Institutions---	Marischal College, Aberdeen
 King\'s College, London
 University of Cambridge
 Alma mater	University of Edinburgh
 University of Cambridge\n\n\n
Academic advisors---	William Hopkins\n\n\n
Notable students---	George Chrystal
John Henry Poynting\n\n\n
Known for---	Maxwell\'s equations\n
Maxwell distribution\n
Maxwell\'s demon\n
Maxwell\'s discs\n
Maxwell speed distribution\n
Maxwell\'s theorem\n
Maxwell material\n
Generalized Maxwell model\n
Displacement current\n
Maxwell coil\n
Maxwell\'s wheel[1]\n\n\n
Notable awards---	Smith\'s Prize (1854)
 Adams Prize (1857)
 Rumford Medal (1860)
 Keith Prize (1869–71)


    </string>
    <string name="interesting_facts_m">
Maxwell\’s contributions played an important role in the advances made in 20th century physics and his work was often admired by fellow physicist Albert Einstein.\n\n\n


        Maxwell attended Edinburgh University from 1847 to 1850. He also spent a large amount of time at his home studying and undertaking various experiments.\n\n\n

After his time at Edinburgh University, Maxwell moved on to Cambridge University where he remained from 1850 to 1856. He further developed his mathematical skills and other ideas before accepting a professorship at Aberdeen University in 1856.\n\n\n

Maxwell was awarded a prize in1859 for his essay \‘On the Stability of Saturn\'s Rings\’, which described the nature of Saturn\’s rings as numerous small particles rather than a solid or fluid ring.\n\n\n


        A large amount of Maxwell\’s research was based on the work of Michael Faraday, and although Maxwell was 40 years younger, the two meet each other on many occasions.\n\n\n

Maxwell also made numerous contributions in the fields of color analysis, kinetic theory and thermodynamics. He is even attributed with creating the first true color photograph.\n\n\n

Famous James Maxwell quotes include: \“Aye, I suppose I could stay up that late.\” – Said after being informed of a compulsory 6 a.m. church service at Cambridge University.\n\n\n

\“In every branch of knowledge the progress is proportional to the amount of facts on which to build, and therefore to the facility of obtaining data.\”
    </string>
    <string name="stories_of_maxwell">


        Saturn\'s Rings\n\n

While at Marischal, Maxwell pondered a major astronomical question, looking at the case of Saturn and coming up with the idea that the planet\'s rings are comprised of particles, a theory later confirmed via 20th-century space probes. For this, Maxwell received the Adam Prize.

Upon Marischal becoming part of the University of Aberdeen, Maxwell took on a professor position at King\'s College in London. He taught there until 1865, when he resigned from his post to do research from his home in Glenlair. Having continued to do work with Cambridge University as well, Maxwell was instrumental in helping to establish the institution\'s Cavendish Laboratory, and he took on roles there as lab director and professor of experimental physics at the start of the 1870s.


    </string>
    <string name="theories_m">
        Electromagnetism\n\n
        Maxwell had studied and commented on electricity and magnetism as early as 1855 when his paper On Faraday\'s lines of force was read to the Cambridge Philosophical Society.[89] The paper presented a simplified model of Faraday\'s work and how the two phenomena were related. He reduced all of the current knowledge into a linked set of differential equations with 20 equations in 20 variables. This work was later published as On Physical Lines of Force in March 1861.[90]\n\n\n\n
         Colour vision\n\n
        As most physicists of the time, Maxwell had a strong interest in psychology. He was particularly interested, following the steps of Isaac Newton and Thomas Young, in the study of colour vision. From 1855 to 1872, he published at intervals a series of investigations concerning the perception of colour, colour-blindness, and colour theory, and was awarded the Rumford Medal for On the Theory of Colour Vision\n\n\n\n

        Kinetic theory and thermodynamics\n\n
        Maxwell also investigated the kinetic theory of gases. Originating with Daniel Bernoulli, this theory was advanced by the successive labours of John Herapath, John James Waterston, James Joule, and particularly Rudolf Clausius, to such an extent as to put its general accuracy beyond a doubt; but it received enormous development from Maxwell, who in this field appeared as an experimenter (on the laws of gaseous friction) as well as a mathematician.[109]




    </string>


    <string name="history_r">

        Born---	22 December 1887\n\n\n
Erode, Madras Presidency (now Tamil Nadu)
Died---	26 April 1920 (aged 32)\n\n\n
Chetput, Madras, Madras Presidency (now Tamil Nadu)
Residence---	Kumbakonam, Tamil Nadu\n\n\n
Nationality---	Indian\n\n\n
Fields---	Mathematics\n\n\n
Education ---Alma mater	Government Arts College (no degree)
 Pachaiyappa\'s College (no degree)
 Trinity College, Cambridge (BSc, 1916)\n\n\n
 Thesis	Highly Composite Numbers (1916)\n\n\n
 Academic advisors	G. H. Hardy
 J. E. Littlewood\n\n\n

Influences	---G. H. Hardy



    </string>
    <string name="interesting_facts_r">

        Ramanujan was born in Erode, Madras, India.\n\n
In 1889 he contracted smallpox but recovered.\n\n
In 1897 he passed his exams in English, Tamil, geography and arithmetic with the highest scores in his district.\n\n
In high school he devoured books on mathematics and discovered advanced theorems.\n\n
In 1903 he read A Synopsis of Elementary Results in Pure and Applied Mathematics by G.S.Carr and it was instrumental in his future discoveries.\n\n
When he was seventeen he developed the Bernoulli numbers and calculated the Euler-Mascheroni constant to 15 decimal places.\n\n
In 1904 he graduated from town Higher Secondary School and received the K. Ranganatha Rao prize in mathematics.\n\n
He received a scholarship to the Government Arts College but failed to study any subject but mathematics and lost his scholarship.\n\n



        In 1918 he was elected Fellow of the Royal Society \"for his investigation in Elliptic function and the Theory of Numbers.\"\n\n
He was diagnosed with tuberculosis and a severe vitamin deficiency but later medical studies point to a case of undiagnosed hepatic amoebiasis.\n\n
He returned to India in 1919 and died in 1920.\n\n





    </string>
    <string name="stories_of_ramanujan">

        TAXICAB NUMBER\n\n
        Well, the story narrates the friendship of the two of the greatest mathematical prodigies of the 20th Century G Hardy and S Ramanujan. The famous Taxi Cab Numbers were discovered that way only.

Hardy once paid a visit to Ramanujan when he was in UK in a cab numbered \"1729\". Ramanujan who had an inherent love for factorization saw the number immediately and said there is something \"fishy\" about it. So came the famous \"Taxicab\" numbers. There are only 6 known taxicab numbers. Hardy and Ramanujan found the second one.

So what are taxicab numbers T(n) are :

They are the smallest numbers which can be represented in n different ways as the sum of n cubes. 1729 happened to be the 2nd \"Taxicab\" no.\n\n

1729=(1^3)+(12^3)\n
        =(9^3)+(10^3)\n\n


        Such was the prodigy of Mr Ramanujan that when once Mr. Hardy was asked bout what was his greatest discovery to mathematics, he replied \"Mr. Ramanujan\"

    </string>
    <string name="theories_r">

    Mock theta functions\n\n\n
    Ramanujan conjecture\n\n\n\n
    Ramanujan prime\n\n\n\n
    Ramanujan–Soldner constant\n\n\n\n
    Ramanujan theta function\n\n\n\n
    Ramanujan\'s sum\n\n\n\n
    Rogers–Ramanujan identities\n\n\n\n
    Ramanujan\'s master theorem\n\n\n\n\n
    Landau–Ramanujan constant\n




</string>


</resources>
